Well, we are still on our EPIC journey, and we have gone through style and delivery in conversation.
But last, but not least, is facilitation.
Facilitation is absolutely critical.
Facilitation means to make something easier.
And that is why effective communicators are also effective facilitators, because they know how to make it easier for other people to understand their message.
Oftentimes people think that being a facilitator means you actually have to lead the discussion,
or that you need to be the content expert in a conversation.
That is not the case. Anyone can be a facilitator.
An effective facilitator comes in with a mindset that is open and curious, and really “over there”. We had discussed this in earlier sessions: the “over there” and the “over here” mindset.
“Over there” is really with your audience, with other people,
thinking about them,
thinking about where they may be, being willing to release your agenda when it’s appropriate,
thinking about asking questions and really uncovering
what else is going on in the room.
Facilitation is equally important whether you are interacting with one
person or a large group. Some of the techniques that we will look at include
the open–narrow–close framework.
This is one way of at least structuring a conversation and understanding a
kind of overall architecture you can use for most conversations.
So there are lots of ways you’ll learn how to use all of the steps from before:
bringing in the empathy, understanding the purpose of that meeting,
drawing out those insights — whether you’re bringing them to the meeting, and others are also contributing those in the interaction —
and bringing that all together in a well-orchestrated conversation.